Their composition is also of great
interest to laboratories.
They search for something unexpected in a
rocky world.
Organic compounds such as amino acids.
If you look at the outside of meteorites,
you can see that as they enter the Earth's
atmosphere,
they can experience some heating and
melting,
but the interior components of the
meteorite that were shielded from the
heating upon entering Earth's atmosphere.
Those are what we're interested in when
we're looking for amino acids.
Every form of life on Earth contains amino
acids, so asteroids are scientific
treasure troves.
Amino acids are the basic subunit that
make up proteins,
and when we study meteorites and we look
for organic compounds like amino acids,
it gives us clues as to what types of
chemical compounds meteorites may have
deposited onto the surface of the Earth.
at or near the time of the origin of life.
Meteorites and asteroids are ambassadors
from a bygone world.
Meteorites are particularly interesting
because they contain a chemical record of
the solar system.
So laboratories collect meteorites to
understand the composition of asteroids or
to try and prove that life on
Earth ...is extraterrestrial in origin.
There are many building blocks of life
that have been found in meteorites to
date, but there are still some that have
not yet been found.
And some of our future research and the
future research in the field will be
focused on finding those missing links
in the building blocks of life.
But scientists have realized that while
meteorites provide clues,
they are not enough to confirm where life
on Earth originated.